proctoru.com 2018-02-16

# Privacy Policy | ProctorU

**Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy describes ProctorU Inc.’s policies and procedures on the collection, use and disclosure of your information you provide on our websites, not limited to the following: https://go.proctoru.com, https://proctoru.com, https://legacy.proctoru.com, and https://blog.proctoru.com. ProctorU Inc. may obtain your information through your use of the service or from your institution. When using any of our Services you consent to the collection, transfer, manipulation, storage, disclosure and other uses of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. Irrespective of which country that you reside in or create information from, your information may be used by ProctorU Inc. in the United States or any other country where ProctorU Inc. operates.

ProctorU Inc. participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. ProctorU Inc. is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s [Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

ProctorU Inc. complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. ProctorU Inc. has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

ProctorU Inc. is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. ProctorU Inc. complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, ProctorU Inc. is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission . In certain situations, ProctorU Inc. may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

If you have a Privacy Shield complaint, please visit <https://support.proctoru.com/hc/en-us> to submit a support ticket.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the [Privacy Shield Website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**Information Collection and Use**

**Information Collected Upon Registration**

When you create or reconfigure a ProctorU Inc. account, you provide some personal information, such as your name, username, password, the institution with which you will be taking an exam, credit card number, access to users’ camera and email address. Some of this information, for example, your name and the assessment you are scheduled to take, is listed internally in our system and is accessible by your institution. Your use of the service may also result in ProctorU Inc. having a stored image of your face, a stored image of the work you perform while connected to ProctorU Inc., or a video capture of your activities while connected with ProctorU Inc. This information is used to verify to your institution that you were the person performing the work and that the work was performed properly.

**Authentication**

You may be asked to authenticate your identity through data services. These questions are generated from a public information database and usually they are scores that indicate the authenticity of users’ identity. The scores are numeric and don’t provide any personal information. Upon request, we will provide you the identity of the authentication service we are using for your account in case you wish to review their privacy policy.

**Log Data**

Our servers automatically record information (“Log Data”) created by your use of the Services. Log Data may include information such as your IP address, browser type, the referring domain, internet service provider (ISP), operating system, date/time stamp, clickstream data, and browser plug-ins.

We use this information to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personal information.

The IP address information we may receive will be the external IP of your ISP and is requested by your partner institution to help troubleshoot issues or verify a general testing location.

**Tracking Technologies**

ProctorU Inc. and our partners use technologies such as cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level.

We use cookies to remember users’ settings. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be limited.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

**Third Party Services**

ProctorU Inc. uses Google Analytics to help understand use of our Services. Google Analytics collects information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, including cookies and your IP address. Google also receives this information and their use of it is governed by their Privacy Policy.

**Social Media Widgets**

Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook, Twitter, Vimeo and WordPress button [and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site]. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

Your Consent: We may share or disclose your information with your institution. Use of ProctorU Inc.’s services explicitly indicates your consent to disclosing your information back to your institution.  
We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us [here](mailto:help@proctoru.com).

These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

**Frames**

Some of our pages utilize framing techniques to serve content to/from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our website. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to www.proctoru.com.

**Service Providers**

We engage certain trusted third parties to perform functions and provide services to us. We may share your personal information with these third parties, but only to the extent necessary to perform these functions and provide such services, and only pursuant to obligations mirroring the protections of this Privacy Policy.

**Law and Harm**

We may disclose your information if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal process; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect ProctorU Inc.’s rights or property.

**Business Transfers**

In the event that ProctorU Inc. is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, your information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

**Modifying Your Personal Information**

Upon request, ProctorU Inc. will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove, ask to have it removed from our site or deactivate it by making the change on your profile page or by emailing our Customer Support at help@proctoru.com or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request to access within a reasonable timeframe.

The telephone number to contact is 855-772-8678. The mailing address is 3687 Old Santa Rita Rd #203 Pleasanton, CA 94588.

**Data Retention**

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Choice/Opt-out**

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or you can contact us at passwords@proctoru.com.

**Links to Other Web Sites**

Our Site includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of ProctorU Inc. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

**Our Policy Towards Children**

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 18. If we become aware that a child under 18 has provided us with personal information, we will delete their information immediately and terminate the child’s account.

**Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us at passwords@proctoru.com.

**Changes to this Policy**

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practice.

**This policy is effective 2/07/17** **.**

**Contact Information**

If you have questions or concerns about this privacy policy, please contact us through the information below:  
ProctorU Inc.  
2200 Riverchase Ctr. Suite 600  
Birmingham, AL 35244  
855-772-8678
